公元2044年
持续增强的太阳风暴使地球表面变成辐射沙漠
使人口激减99.7%至210万
大气的损坏使大多数无线电通讯失效
使科技文明进入"大衰退"
在恐惧与绝望中
ROC公司推出机器人PILGRIM7000
最初的这批机器人被用于建墙
以保护人类在仅存的城市中繁衍生息
现在 数以万计的机器人通过2条原则被人类使用着
第一
机器人不能伤害任何生命
第二
机器人不能改造自己或其他机器人
两条原则为保护人类而生
它们是不可篡改的
气象计划将在32分16秒后开始执行
Meteorological program duration will be 32 minutes and 16 seconds.
机械云将在10秒后带来强降雨
Mechanical clouds will induce heavy rainfall in 10 seconds.
雨水酸化水平估计在8.4
Water acidification level estimated at 8.4.
东南部地区中央天气晴朗
Clear skies over Central Sector in Southeast Perimeter.
ROC公司7000型PILGRIM机器人
机器人会保护我们  PILGRIM=未来
带我们走出沙漠
阻止沙漠化  上PILGRIM
PILGRIM之桥
PILGRIM无法阻止沙漠化
废物  去你的PILGRIM
你知道这是什么吗
Do you know what this is?
这简直没法活了
It's the fucking end of the world.
我只告诉那个东西给查理刷毛
All I told him was brush him.
查理  只是一条可爱的小狗
Brush Charlie. He was a good dog.
查理很听话  我们很爱他  不能没有他
Loving, obedient. There can't be many left like him.
最重要的是  查理是我妻子最好的朋友
But above all, he was my wife's best friend!
你们公司怎么样才能抚平我们心中的痛苦
How could your company repair our suffering,
武尔坎先生
Mr. Vaucan?
这样的爱要怎么用金钱衡量
How could ROC put a price to that kind of love?
喂
Hello?
不好意思  先生
Excuse me, sir.
读取我的证件
Read my card.
举起你的右手  是的  先生
Raise your right arm. Yes, sir.
握住我的手
Grab my hand.
使劲握
Grab it hard.
使劲
Harder.
你不相信我
You don't believe me.
我付保险费是有目的你知道
I paid a premium for something, you know.
我的保险范围包括整个...
And my policy coverage includes the whole...
家庭成员
family unit.
查理也是家人  但是那个东西杀了查理
Charlie was family unit and that thing killed him.
杀了查理吗  先生  是的  是的
Killed him, sir? Yes. Yes.
小心点  先生
Be careful, sir.
您手上拿着的工具
The instrument that you are handling
可能会威胁到您的健康
could be a threat for your health.
我很高兴地通知你
I am thrilled to inform you
您机器人的状态非常好
that your unit is in perfect condition.
他是这个厨房里
It's the only one in this kitchen
唯一不会杀生的东西  即使你逼他
who couldn't harm a living being, even if you force it to.
什么  他妈的  你在暗示什么
What the fuck are you insinuating?
我告诉过你  阿斯科
I told you, Askol.
闭嘴
Shut up.
这只狗是我们的家人
That dog was family unit.
这样的情绪不像是
It is very emotional to see there are still people
深爱着家庭的人
who care so deeply about family.
欢迎  武尔坎先生
Welcome, Mr. Vaucan.
嗨
Hi.
如果你能数数  你就能跳舞
If you can count, you can dance.
下个星期一是新月
Next Monday is a new moon.
我妹妹说  当新月的时候孩子就出生了
My sister says I'll give birth then, when the moon changes.
我一直在想  当我回去工作的时候...
I've been thinking that when I go back to work...
我们就该请个佣人了
we should have a domestic.
我相信公司能给我们找个体面的
I'm sure the company can get us a decent one.
真希望孩子跟随着新月出世
I hope it comes with the new moon.
-你会数吗  -当然
-Can you count? -Of course.
和我一起数  一  二  三  四
Then count with me. One, two, three, four.
跳舞就像数学  你会数数  你就会跳舞
Dancing is mathematical. If you can count, you can dance.
...将导致太阳辐射在1.25度
...will cause solar radiation at 1.25 degrees.
在墙体附近
Along the retaining wall during most of the days.
白天污染物微粒的含量
The contaminating particles, concentration levels
将维持在...
will remain stable at or around...
新信息
6:30 警察暴动
日光将在12点前不可见
Daylight will not be visible until after 12 noon.
那是个PILGRIM7000  是CCA财产
It's a Pilgrim 7000, property of CCA...
外墙的承建公司
the construction company in charge of the outer wall.
发现它的警察说它出了故障
The policeman who found it said it was malfunctioning
不得不使用暴力关闭它
and had to disconnect it using violence.
他开枪了
He shot it.
-什么  -他开枪了
-What? -He shot it.
报告说这是正当防卫
The report says it was self-repairing.
正当防卫  对一个机器人  你应该给他做个测试
Self-repairing? The unit? You should have run a few tests on the cop.
我们做了  酒精和甲胺测试呈阳性
We did. Positive for alcohol and methylamine.
他目前正在接受调查
He's currently under investigation.
那个白痴知道这个东西值多少钱么
Does that moron know how much this little toy is worth?
该死
Goddamn it.
表面看上去没多大变化
You can't see any big changes at first sight,
但是它的内部被大幅修改了
but there's been significant alterations performed inside the carcass.
有人对它动了手脚
Someone's had fun with this toy.
系统变流器被改动了
The power system converter's been manipulated.
他们加了第二个直流电池作备用
They've added a second DC battery as a back-up.
而且...
And...
补偿液也是新的
the compensation fluid is also new.
序列号没有被删除
The serial numbers haven't been erased.
它们都完好无损
They're all intact.
我们能找到它们的来源吗
Can we track them down?
事实上
In fact,
有其他机器人也在使它们的序列号
it has parts of other units which also keep their serial numbers.
无聊的工作
Crappy job.
恰好相反  这是一个非常复杂的工作
Quite the contrary. This is a very sophisticated job.
要我说  做手脚的人就是个机械师
I'd say it's a clocksmith.
虽然看起来他不在意
Although it looks like he wasn't concerned
隐藏元件的来源
about hiding the origin of the parts.
仿生内核怎么样了
What about the Biokernel?
它头部中了一枪  把它烧了
It's had a shot in the head. The Biokernel's fried.
不过  从我们在它身边发现的东西来看...
But judging by what was found next to it...
我觉得这台机器人的软件
I think it's quite safe to say that this unit's software
很可能被篡改来偷工具和零件了
was altered to smuggle tools and parts.
这是给你的
This is for you.
这啥
What is this?
账单
The bill.
ROC公司是不会为这堆垃圾付账的
ROC is not going to pay for all of this bullshit.
这是件没有主人的私改品
This is an altered unit without an owner.
私改品就是非法品
An altered unit is an illegal unit.
在这事消停之前
And until this conflict is solved,
ROC保险公司要为这期间的开销买单
ROC's insurance will have to cover the expenses.
而且根据那份报告
Besides, according to that report,
这机器人没有第二条原则
this is a unit without a second protocol.
这简直不可能...
Oh, you know that's plain stupid, right?
的确  但这次非比寻常
Sure. But unusual stupidity.
我从没见过这样的事
I've never seen this before.
杰克这堆废铁就是块烫手山芋
Jack, this clunker is a sticky mess
但总有人要接手的
and somebody's got to clean it up.
不过绝不是我
And believe me, I will not be that someone.
一个没有第二条原则的机器人
A unit without the second protocol?
这傻帽警察
Cop is nuts.
他当时嗑嗨了
He was high.
他说这台机器人当时在维修自己
He said the unit was repairing itself.
-那货当时嗑嗨了  -但事实是有人改动了他
-The guy was high. -The fact is that someone altered it. Maybe...
或许是个贫民区的机械师
a clocksmith in the ghetto.
机械师
Clocksmiths.
杰克  我们不是警察
We're not cops, Jack.
我们就是保险业务员
We're just insurance agents.
鲍伯  我在想也许...
Bob, I was thinking...
我能离开街道一段时间
about staying away from the streets for a little while.
离开这些脏兮兮的事儿
Staying away from all the filth.
你想干嘛  调职
What do you want, a transfer?
有人说海边的环境会好点
Well, they say things are better on the Coast.
海边
The Coast?
现如今大家都过得不怎么样
Things are hard for everybody.
你也知道公司现在很困难
The company is struggling, you know that.
和政府的合同还没着落
Contract with the city is up in the air.
现在正是大干一场的时候  而不是收拾走人
Now is the time to pitch in, not pack up.
我太累了
I am burnt out.
真的再也受不了了
Can't take this anymore.
你好好看看你自己
Take a look at yourself.
你就没想过你有多幸运
Have you ever considered how fortunate you are?
你有一份不错的工作  住的地方也不错
You got a good job. You live in a great pod.
你还有一份健康保险
You have health insurance
能让你和瑞秋生个漂亮的闺女
that allows you and Rachel to have a beautiful baby girl.
这日子已经很好了  杰克
It's a good life, Jack.
而你还要做什么才能维持现状吗
And you know all you have to do to keep it?
找个帮你管着烂摊子的人
Find someone else to hold accountable for this mess.
就这样
Just that.
别老往坏处看
Quit looking in the garbage so much.
你就能知道你有多幸运了
Maybe you'll see how really lucky a guy you are.
让我捋一捋
Let me get this straight.
我7000型机器人中的一个
One of my 7000s has been found
被逮到在非法交易零件
trafficking stolen parts?
而且那批铁皮还松了几个螺丝
Not only that, but the poor clunker has one or two loose screws?
这简直荒唐
That's dramatic.
那台被射杀的7000型机器人身上
The 7000 that was shot had 25 different parts
有25个部件不属于他
that didn't belong in it.
其中的一些零件就是从  在这工作的机器人身上摘的
Some of which are from units that also worked here.
还有呢  或许...
And? Well, maybe...
你的某个员工试着改变...
one of your employees tried to change or...
改造这些机器人
modify the unit.
只有ROC公司才能维修这些机器人
Only ROC can repair robots.
只有这样我们才能保障安全
That's how we can guarantee security, sir.
安全个屁
Security, my ass.
你们的机器人干活一天比一天差
Your units work worse and worse every day.
一个好的还被一人渣偷了
The ones that aren't broken are stolen by that scum.
所以如果你真这么关心安全问题
So, if you're so concerned about security,
何不自己去排查那堆垃圾
why don't you disinfect that dump?
狗屁保险
Fucking insurance.
我们见一个杀一个
We shoot on sight.
他们明知道这儿属于保密范围
They know it's a restricted area.
我们所做的一切
All the work we do here
都是为了防那种人渣
is trying to prevent that scum
以免他入侵城市
from invading the city.
我以为墙是建来阻隔沙漠的
I thought the wall was built to protect us from the desert.
当然  飞机哪天也能上天
Sure. And planes will fly again one day.
这是什么
And what is this crap?
这零件是一个还在岗的7000型机器人的
These pieces are from a 7000 that's operative.
206号  第五区的焊接工
Number 206, a welder in Section 5.
焊接工206号正在工作
Welder 206 currently on duty.
警告
Warning.
你正离开城市警戒线
You are leaving the city limits
进入禁止区域
and entering in a restricted area.
至此城市将不再对您的安全负责
From this point on, the city is not responsible of your security.
别开枪
Don't shoot!
你手里拿的是什么
What do you have in there?
What do you have in there? What do you have in there?
你是说那个机器人离开了自己的工作区域...
So, the unit leaves its assigned workplace and...
然后放了把火...
escapes to set itself on fire...
把自己点着了
on its own.
你是认真的
Are you serious?
他在盒子里放了些什么
What was it keeping inside the box?
有几件工具
We have a few tools here.
这应该是...
These could be remains of...
热传感器的部件
heat sensors.
而这个就像是...
And I'd say this seems to be a...
一个核能电池  在"大衰败"前
It's a nuclear battery. Before the regression,
人们用它来驱动卫星
they used them to move satellites.
这是种强大的电池  同时非常难找
It's a very powerful battery and very hard to come by.
你能把它安在机器人上吗
Can you install that in a Pilgrim?
如果你想把它烧坏的话
Only if you want to barbecue it.
不止如此
It's much more than that.
在找机械能源的人
Anyone that's looking for autonomous power sources...
会想要它们的
will appreciate them.
它能听见我们说话吗
Can it hear us?
应该能
It should.
读取我的证件
Read my badge.
说明你的身份
Identify yourself.
B-2  206  焊接组
B-2 206. Welder Section.
好
All right.
我们在你手上找到这块电池
We found this battery in your hands.
谁让你偷的
Who asked you to steal it?
找到这块电池
Found this battery.
你正往贫民区走
You were going to the ghetto.
在那儿等你的是你的主人吗
Was your owner waiting for you there?
我没有主人  先生
I do not have an owner, sir.
你为什么烧自己
Why did you set yourself on fire?
你为什么...
Why did you set yourself...
该死  武尔坎
Shit, Vaucan.
你先是烤了它...
First you roast it.
现在你把它弄哭了
Now you make it cry.
马上  我就会接到一通要求我解释的电话
Soon, I'm going to get a call asking for an explanation.
我见这些被篡改的机器人多了
I have seen altered units for years.
但我对你发誓  今天这个不一样
But I swear to you, what I've seen today is different.
它不一样了...你一定是疯了
It's something else. You're definitely nuts.
你以为上层这几天是怎么想的
What kind of mood do you think the boys upstairs are in these days?
如果我们不把城市合约搞定
If we don't get the city to renew our contract,
我们就等着喝西北风吧
we're all going down the tube.
我知道  我知道
Okay, okay!
如果我找到那个始作俑者了呢
What if I find the clocksmith behind all this?
这都是因为调职的事
It's about the transfer.
这都是因为调职的事  是不是
This is all about the transfer, isn't it?
上帝啊  杰克
Oh, Jesus, Jack.
既然如此
Very well.
改掉你的报告  找到犯人  把案子结了
Change your report, find me a culprit, close the case,
我就让你调职
and you will have your farewell ticket.
谁知道呢  杰克
Who knows, Jack?
没准大海还在呢
Maybe the ocean is still there.
第一台机器人出世的那一天  我爸把我带到这来
My old man brought me here the day the first unit came out.
23年前了
23 years ago.
那时的对话我记忆犹新
I remember exactly what they said back then.
PILGRIM为帮助人类
The Pilgrims were born to help us
解决生存问题而生
in our heroic quest for survival.
现在它们为我们造房子  帮我们开车
Now they build our homes, drive our cars,
当我们老了为我们料理后事
and wipe our asses when we get old.
我跟本不知道接下来该干什么了
I have no idea what we're going to do next.
撤销那两条原则~
Maybe eliminate the protocols.
肯定的
Sure.
试着想象下...
Imagine for a moment...
那个机器人把自己点着了...
that the unit had set itself on fire. No, I...
不不不  你就想想看...
No, no, just, just, just imagine.
如果它对自己行使暴力...
If it was using violence against itself...
这就是在违反第二条原则啊
it would actually be breaking the second protocol, wouldn't it?
技术上讲  是的  但还有个小问题
Of course, technically. But the little problem
原则植入在仿生内核里
is the protocols reside within the Biokernel,
并且都经过量子加密
which itself is based on a quantum encryption.
它的安全系统是条单向道
Their security system is a one-way road.
一旦更改原则  就会毁坏仿生内核
If you try and change the protocols, you destroy the Biokernel.
这就像把肥皂泡放在口袋里
It's kind of like trying to keep a soap bubble in your pocket.
没人干过因为这根本不可能
No one's ever done it before because you simply can't.
你明白吗
Do you get it?
嘿
Hey.
里面的世界怎么样
How's everything in there?
外边有人等不及要给你换尿布了
There are people out here who are looking forward to changing your diapers.
有人一夜不想合眼
People who don't want to sleep a wink all night.
有人想结束这片沉寂
People who want the silence to be over.
欢迎  武尔坎先生
Welcome, Mr. Vaucan.
哇
Wow.
她看起来很高兴见到你
Looks like she's happy to see you.
你猜她会不会介意我带他妈妈出去吃饭
Do you think she'd mind if I take her mom out to dinner?
我猜想今晚你一定有些特殊的好理由
I guess there must be a good reason for such a special night.
我们就要有孩子了  这就是个好理由
We are going to be a family. That is a good reason.
离开这个地方也是个好理由
Maybe leaving this place could be another good reason.
离开  去哪
Leaving? Where?
你感受过海边的微风吗
Have you ever felt the breeze of the ocean?
我知道我们以前谈过  但现在不一样了
I know we have already talked about this. But now it's different.
现在我们有机会离开这里了
Now there's a real opportunity to get out of here.
鲍伯会帮我调职
Bob can get me a transfer.
瑞秋
Rachel.
之后我们又要去干什么呢
And what are we going to do?
在限期前坐上公车去另一座城市
Get on a bus and start from scratch
让一切从头开始
in another city with an expiration date?
-你就要有女儿了杰克  -我知道
-You're about to have a daughter, Jack. -I know. I know.
-所以你到底想去哪  -一个还有未来的地方
-Where the hell do you want to go? -Where there is a damn future.
未来肯定就在某个地方
There has to be one somewhere.
你怎么知道在海边日子就会比较好
How do you know it'll be any better on the coast?
看在上帝的份上瑞秋  你好好看看这个地方
For God's sake, Rachel, look at this. Look.
空气无法呼吸  雨水无法触碰
Air we cannot breathe. Rain we cannot touch.
你难道就不怕把女儿带到这样的地方
Aren't you afraid to bring your daughter into a place like this?
你怎么变得这么可悲
How can you be such a wretch?
我已经无法承受担惊受怕
I can't afford to be afraid.
告诉我你不后悔...
Tell me you don't regret it.
告诉我  杰克
Tell me, Jack.
是你坚持要的
You insisted.
确实  是我自找的
That's true, I insisted.
现在  请你滚出这儿
Now, get out of here, please.
-瑞秋...-让我一个人待会...
-Rachel... -Leave me alone.
请小心  先生
Be careful, sir.
雨水有害您的健康
The rain can be hazardous to your health.
拜托了  先生
Please, sir.
我的主人很饿  拜托了先生
My owner is hungry. Please, sir.
你是小机的朋友吗
Are you a friend of Bot's?
小机是个好机器人
Bot was kind.
我没撒谎
I ain't fooling anybody.
我确实偶尔会夸大事实
Yeah, I crank up once in a while.
我们都这么干  但这事儿有下线
We all do over here, but I know the limits.
而且我分得清那机器人是在修管子
And I definitely know the difference between a clunker welding a pipe
还是在修自己的腿
and another one welding his fucking leg.
能证明你没疯的唯一方式
The only way to prove you're not crazy
就是找到那个改动了机器人的机械师
is to find the clocksmith who altered that unit.
是的  我明白
Yeah, right. Maybe,
没准华莱士你该在报纸上登个广告
Wallace, you should place an ad in the paper
或者更好的是
or better yet,
换个毒贩子
find a new dealer.
爱怎么想怎么想
Yeah, think what you want,
但我真看见那个机器人掏自己内脏了
but I saw that clunker turn its guts inside out.
就这样
End of story.
该死  滚开
Fucking cripple. Get out of the road!
你的想法就是命令  先生
Your wish is my command, sir.
你这块废铁  快滚
Piece of shit, move!
该死的废物
Fucking animals.
它在盯着我
It was staring at me.
举起它的手  就像它知道在发生什么一样
Hid its hands like that motherfucker was fully aware.
它在干些不该干的事
It was doing something it wasn't supposed to do.
埃利斯  我不是因为它盯着我看才开枪的
Ellis, I didn't shoot that clunker because it was staring at me.
我开枪是因为...
I shot it because...
我开枪是因为它看起来...
I shot it because it looked...
像活的
Alive?
我是认真的
I was being serious.
你看的只可能是机械师的杰作  还是个厉害的
What you saw can only be the work of a clocksmith. A good one at that.
想不被人当傻子
The only way they won't take you for a fool
就找到他
is to find him.
我不了解城里  但在这儿
I don't know about the city, but here, among the filth,
贫民窟里  机械师可不好找
clocksmiths aren't listed in the phone books.
你甚至无从找起
You wouldn't even know where to begin.
好吧  或许...
Well, maybe...
核能电池能帮上忙
a nuclear battery would help.
你有核能电池
You have a nuclear battery?
克莱奥.
Cleo
你命令  她服从
You ask, she obeys.
这机器人能干这事儿
This unit can do these things?
克莱奥  你问她好吗
Cleo. You ask her, okay?
别害怕
Do not be afraid.
我能完美区别愉快与疼痛
I can distinguish perfectly between pleasure and pain.
你能制造疼痛吗
Can you cause pain?
如果你想要的话
Only if it's your wish.
你改动过它
Have you altered it?
-克莱奥  没有问题  -给她看电池
-Cleo is all okay. -Show her the battery.
-不  直到我知道她就是那个人之前  -嘿  你
-No, not until I know she's the one we're looking for. -Hey, you.
我们要见给你造这垃圾的人
We need to meet who made you this piece of filth.
不是垃圾  克莱奥比你老婆还厉害
No filth. Cleo better than your wife.
我已经没有老婆了
I don't have a wife anymore.
-嘿  冷静点  -闭嘴
-Hey, come on. -Shut up!
那个机械师是谁
Come on. Who the fuck's the clocksmith?
没有机械师  滚  滚  滚
No clocksmith! Out! Out! Out!
那个机械师是谁
Who's the clocksmith?
你TM到底在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
克莱奥  克莱奥
Cleo! Cleo!
嘿
Hey!
克莱奥  克莱奥
Cleo. Cleo.
嘿  你为什么开枪
Hey! Why did you do that?
滚开
Get off.
-我们就快得手了  -我叫你把手拿开
-We almost got it. -I said get your hands off me!
就算你揍死那个狗娘养的
You could be clobbering the shit out of that dimwit son of a bitch.
她也不会告诉你她的名字
She wouldn't even tell you her own name.
现在  你只要等她把它带到商店里
You just have to wait for her to take it to the shop.
你的机械师就在那里
Your clocksmith will be there.
听着  我为你冒了很大的风险杰克
Listen, I've risked more than I should have for you, Jack.
你最好准备好我的酬劳
You better get my cut ready.
我什么都不会给你
I am not paying you shit.
别TM想吓唬我
And don't even think about threatening me, you son of a bitch.
你最好准备我的那份
You better get my cut ready.
不然  下次让我见到你...
If not, next time I see you...
我就切断你的喉咙
maybe I cut your throat.
我没带武器
I am not armed.
我知道  你想干什么
I know that. What do you want?
我是ROC保险部门的
I work for ROC insurance department.
我在追查两起机器人私改行为
I'm tracking down some alterations performed on two units.
这是其中一个机器人的内核
This is one of the unit's kernel.
警察不知道该拿它怎么办
The police doesn't know what to do with it
而我也无法从ROC得到任何帮助
and I am not getting any help from ROC.
帮我...
Help me out...
这块电池就归你
and the battery is yours.
这块内核已经烧坏了
That kernel is burnt.
那台机器人中枪了
That unit was shot.
开枪的警察说它在维修自己
The cop who shot it swears it was repairing itself.
第二台被改动的机器人在我面前自焚了
The second altered unit set itself on fire right in front of me.
我亲眼所见
I witnessed with my own eyes
它对第二原则的违背
a violation of the second protocol.
你吓到我了...
You're beginning to frighten me now.
这听起来就这么荒唐
Why is it so absurd?
如果有人能让这些吸尘器...
If somebody could find a way for the vacuum cleaners to...
自我维修...
fix themselves,
ROC就会破产
ROC would sink.
机械的自我维修是个非常复杂的概念
A machine altering itself is a very complex concept.
自我维修反映了某种意义上的意识
Self-repairing implies some idea of a conscience.
无从解释
Muddy waters.
为什么
Why?
你今天送来核能电池
You're here today trafficking in nuclear goods
因为很久以前有只猴子
because a long time ago
决定从树上下来了
a monkey decided to come down from a tree.
大脑从猿类
Transitioning from the brain of an ape
进化到你现在的认知能力
to your incredible intellectual prowess...
花了我们700万年的时间
took us about seven million years.
这是条很长的路
It's been a very long road.
但一台没有第二原则的机器人
A unit, however, without the second protocol
能在几周内完成这种进化
could travel that same road in just a few weeks.
因为你的大脑是受限的
Because your brilliant brain has its limitations.
生理和心理都受限
Physical limitations. Biological limitations.
但在这个铁皮脑袋里
However, this tin head?
唯一的限制就是她的第二原则
The only limitations that she has is the second protocol.
第二原则之所以存在是因为
The second protocol exists because we don't know
我们不知道逾越了它会发生什么
what can be beyond the second protocol.
一旦原则被解除  天知道机器人会发展成什么样
If it were eliminated, who knows how far that vacuum could go.
-所以这是可能的  -我可没这么说
-So, it can be done. -I didn't say that.
总之  我不认识有这种能力的人
Anyway, I don't know anybody good enough to do something like that.
-你叫什么  -对你而言  杜普雷博士
-What's your name? -For you, Dr. Duprè.
好的  杜普雷博士
All right, Dr. Duprè.
我去过贫民窟
I have been to the ghetto.
我目睹了机器人的"归宿"
I have seen how the units end up.
我也知道了克莱奥的能力所及
I have seen how far Cleo is capable of going.
克莱奥能比其他机器人更了解人类
Cleo is capable of understanding human nature better than other units.
但别担心  没人动过它的原则
But don't worry. No one has messed with its protocols.
或许吧
Maybe.
但我不认为下树
But I am not so sure if coming down from the tree
就是为了我们今天的结论
was worth it just to get to where we are.
谢谢你
Thank you.
欢迎  武尔坎先生
Welcome, Mr. Vaucan.
杰克 武尔坎. 443 441.
Jack  Vaucan  443  441
资产内部报告  罗伯特·布罗德收  113  111
Priority internal report for Robert Bold, 113 111.
我对贫民窟的机械师杜普雷博士
I've authorized an external evaluation
授权了仿生内核的外部评鉴
of the Biokernel to a Dr. Duprè, a clocksmith in the ghetto.
她或许能找到篡改机器人者的蛛丝马迹
She may be able to find some trace of the manipulation of the unit,
即使排除了第二原则被篡改的
even dismiss the possibility that the second protocol could have
可能性
been suppressed.
正在发送至ROC  527  234
Sending report to ROC 527 234.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我会去任何必要的地方  我不在乎了
I'll go wherever's necessary. I don't care.
但你必须明白  真正的未来在这儿
But you have to understand that the only real future is right here.
而我必须知道你会为此而战
And I need to know that you will fight for it.
我对你发誓  我在尽我最大的努力了
I swear to you I am trying as hard as I can.
我非钢铁...
I'm not made of steel.
我需要你
I need you.
再过几天吧瑞秋  过几天我们就走
A couple of days, Rachel. Just give me a couple of days and we'll leave.
人生总在寻找他的路杰克
Life always ends up finding its way, Jack.
即使在这儿
Even here.
霍克先生...
Mr. Hawk...
杰克·武尔坎  我们的雇员之一
Jack Vaucan, one of our employees,
一小时前给罗伯特·布罗德发的信息
sent this message to Robert Bold an hour ago.
你看着办吧康韦
Take care of it, Mr. Conway.
来自弗农·康韦的信息
Incoming message from Vernon Conway.
调查取消
立即撤回PILGRIM机器人仿生内核与文件
来自苏珊·杜普雷的信息
Incoming message from Susan Duprè.
你的机器人从树上下来了
你从哪找到的仿生内核
Where did you get that Biokernel?
怎么了  你查到什么了吗
Why? You found something?
仿生内核受损了  但还没全坏
That Biokernel was damaged, but it wasn't dead.
所以我用剩下的部分
So, I thought, why not make a hybrid
弄了个"混血儿"
with the usable part of your kernel
把它放到标准的内核放到一起
and I put it with a standard kernel.
-然后呢  -然后我把它安装到克莱奥身上了
-And? -And I installed it in Cleo.
刚装上的时候它没有任何反应
When I first installed the kernel, she didn't even blink.
半个小时后我发现它在看自己的手
After half an hour, I found her looking at her hands.
然后它自己一路爬到了这儿
Then, she crawled all the way here by herself.
现在  它花了
And now it's taken her
1小时10分钟给自己装了条新腿
an hour and 10 minutes to attach a brand new leg.
而这花了我好几年
It took me years to know how to do that.
她在干嘛
What is she doing?
偷东西
She's stealing.
她很挑剔
And she's being very selective.
我以为你是一个人
I thought you came alone.
我叫了辆计程车等我
I told the cabbie to wait outside.
好吧我去去就来
Okay, well, that could come in handy.
好好看着她
Keep your eye on her.
你是苏珊·杜普雷
Are you Susan Duprè?
对你  杜普雷博士  你想干嘛
To you, Dr. Duprè. What do you want?
还有一个
There's another one!
嘿  等等
Hey! Wait! Wait!
住手  先生
Stop, sir.
您正在危害一个人的生命
You are putting a human life in danger.
住手  先生  您正在危害一个人的生命
Stop, sir. You are putting a human life in danger.
他们正往沙垒跑
They're heading to the Sandbox.
该死
Oh, shit!
帮我一把
Help me.
城市在哪
Where's the city?
Where is the city?
等等  等等  停下来
Wait, wait. Stop.
我命令你停下来
I told you to stop.
很好
Good. Good. Good.
我的名字是杰克·武尔坎
My name is Jack Vaucan.
编号443  441
Code 443 441.
这是直接命令  我要你立刻执行
This is a direct order and I want you to execute it.
掉头带我回城市
Turn around now and take me to the city.
对不起武尔坎先生  城市对你我而言不安全
Sorry, Mr. Vaucan. The city is not safe for any of us.
你被篡改了
You have been altered.
你到底要去哪
Where the hell are you going?
一个安全的地方
To a safer place.
您必须保存体力  请坐这儿
You must save your energy. Please sit here.
带我回城市
Take me to the city.
那里什么也没有  什么也没有
There is nothing there. Nothing!
对不起先生  回城是不可能的
Please, sir. Going back to the city is not possible.
不可能
It's not possible?
你以为你是谁  说什么不可能
Who are you to say it's not possible?
住手  先生  您正在危害一个人的生命
Stop, sir. You are putting a human life in danger.
我们不能去城市先生
We cannot go to the city, sir.
危险  先生  我们不能让您这样做
Danger. Please, sir. We cannot allow you to do that.
住手  先生  您正在危害一个人的生命
Stop, sir. You are putting a human life in danger.
武尔坎的设备目前不可用
Mr. Vaucan's device is not operative at the moment.
信息将被...
The message will...
我们制造了一个滤水器
We have made a water condenser.
第一原则要求我们保护您
Our first protocol demands that we protect you.
日出时您会有更多水
There will be more water for you at dawn.
发生什么了
What's going on?
我们不能让您死
We can't let you die.
如果您想活下去  您必须跟我们在一起
If you want to survive, you must stay with us.
回城是不可能的
Going back to the city is not possible.
你目睹过奇迹吗  布罗德先生
Have you ever witnessed a miracle before, Mr. Bold?
那个机器人的仿生内核
That robot unit has the Biokernel
来自你的人焚毁的机器人
from the unit your man burned installed in it.
这怎么可能
How is this possible?
这就是最令人惊奇的部分
That's the astonishing part.
有人成功地...
Someone has managed to...
篡改了它的第二原则
eliminate the second protocol.
武尔坎跟这没关系
Vaucan has nothing to do with this.
如果武尔坎跟这事没关系
If Vaucan had nothing to do with this...
那他为什么今早没出现
why did he not show up this morning?
他为什么要烧那台垃圾
Why did he burn that clunker?
他为什么要联系那个杜普雷
Why did he contact that Duprè?
更重要的是...
And most important...
其他被篡改过的仿生内核TM的在哪
where the fuck is the other altered Biokernel?
你知道一旦内核被篡改会发生什么吗
Do you know what happens once that is altered?
2个被篡改的会试着篡改第3个
Two of them then try to alter a third one.
星星之火
Then the miracle dissipates...
可以燎原
and the epidemic begins.
杰克对公司很忠诚
Jack is loyal to this company, that's all I can tell you.
布罗德先生...
Mr. Bold...
你想过你有多幸运吗
have you ever considered just how fortunate you are?
你需要蛋白质
You need protein.
你从车上拿了点东西对吧
You took stuff from the car, right?
没准里面有真正的食物
Maybe there is some real food there.
你能给我拿点水吗
Bring me some of that water, will you?
好帮我把这玩意咽下去
I need something to help these go down.
冷凝流程进行得很缓慢
The condenser works slowly.
不不不
No, no, no.
再我点
Bring me some more.
已经没有水了  冷凝过程很缓慢
There is no more water. The condenser works slowly.
再过几小时会有更多水
In a few hours it will make more water.
再过几小时我就死了
I may be dead in a few hours.
你叫克莱奥对吧
Your name is Cleo, right?
好  听着  克莱奥  这片沙漠的辐射很强
Well, listen, Cleo, this desert is a highly radioactive place.
而我没有任何保护措施
And I don't have any protection.
所以如果我死在这  就等于你杀了我
So, if I die here, it would be the same as if you would kill me.
来自 杰克 的信息
沙垒以西25英里
沙垒
The Sandbox?
你朋友摊上大麻烦了
Your friend's in deep shit.
我不知道发生了什么
I don't know what's going on here.
但我要你去把他找回来
But I want you to go out there and find him and bring him back here.
办妥了我就把你的记录销掉
Do it and we'll clean your file.
当然  先生
Of course, sir.
为人民服务
To serve and protect.
你听得懂我说什么吗
You speak my language?
你有保险吗
Are you insured?
我去去就回
I'll be right back.
该死  华莱士  他们正往辐射区去
Oh, shit. Wallace, they're going toward the radioactive area.
往里走只会越来越糟
The deeper we go in that direction, the worse it's going to get.
停
Stop!
人类间的事
Human business.
停
Stop.
别动
Hold still!
我最后再命令你一次
I will tell you one last time.
再走一步我就爆你头
One more step and I will blow you up.
-我们不能去城市  先生  -该死
-We cannot go to the city, sir. -Goddamn it.
我叫你别动
I told you to hold still!
如果我们回城我们就会死
If we go back to the city, we will die.
未生勿能死
To die, you have to be alive first.
你
You?
终于  我从没想过再见你会这么开心
Finally. I never thought I'd be happy to see you again.
再见你我也很高兴  杰克
Good to see you, too, Jack.
你到底在干嘛
What the hell are you doing?
应该是我问你  你TM的在干嘛
The right question is, what the fuck are you doing?
你可不能到处把人惹毛
You can't go around pissing people off.
你找到你的机械师了吗杰克
You find your clocksmith, Jack?
你根本不知道这儿发生了什么
You have no idea what's happening here.
我想我知道
I think maybe I do, huh?
把电池还给我  先生
Give us back our battery, sir.
请您把电池还给我  先生
Please, sir. Give us back our battery.
拜托您  先生  我们需要电池
Please, sir, we need our battery.
拿着
Keep that.
你这么干到底为什么  杰克
What the fuck is this about, Jack?
你明知道我讨厌这些垃圾
You know I hate these fucking clunkers!
带我回城
Take me to the city.
住手  先生  你正威胁一个人的生命
Stop, sir. You are putting a human life in danger.
我们正说着你的机械师呢
We were talking about your clocksmith.
你到底在藏什么  "一飞冲天先生"
Where are you hiding Mr. Big Shot?
住手  先生  你正威胁一个人的生命
Stop, sir. You are putting a human life in danger.
对不起先生  我们不能让您这么做
Please, sir. We cannot allow you to do that.
还有谁
Somebody else?
住手  先生  你正威胁一个人的生命
Stop, sir. You are putting a human life in danger.
这不就上次那个小婊子吗
Oh, isn't this the little whore I met last time?
你都开始上机器人了杰克
You getting off on clunkers now, Jack?
住手  先生  你正威胁一个人的生命
Stop, sir. You are putting a human life...
Stop, sir. You are putting a human life in danger.
-住手  先生  -我们不能让您这么做
-Stop, sir. -We will not allow you to...
-住手  先生  -嘿  嘿  带我回城
-Stop, sir. -Hey! Hey! Take me to the city!
等等  别我丢下  我要回城
Wait! Don't leave me here! I have to go back to the city!
-等等  -住手  先生
-Wait! Wait! -Stop, sir.
-该死  -您在危害一个人的生命
-Goddamn it! Shit! -You are putting a human life...
住手  先生
Stop, sir. Stop, sir. Stop, sir.
我们不能让您这么做  住手  先生
We cannot allow you to do that. Stop, sir.
秃鹰
Vultures.
他们就像秃鹰
They are like vultures.
嗨
Hi.
你一定要帮我回去
You've got... you've got to help me go back.
我一定要回城解释这发生的一切
I need to go back to the city and explain what is happening.
我是个人类
I'm a human.
你听到了吗
Did you hear me?
我是个人类
I am human!
你必须服从我
You have to obey me!
城市在那边
The city is that way!
我们到底要去哪
Where the hell are we going?
你要把我带去哪
Where the hell are you taking me?
该死
Goddamn it!
什么
What?
警察把你的电池拿走了
The policeman took your battery.
但我还有一个
But I have another one.
带我回城
Take me to the city...
我就把它给你
and I'll give it to you.
我老婆怀孕了
My wife is pregnant.
我就快有孩子了
I'm going to have a baby.
我们明天将抵达终点
We will arrive at our destination tomorrow.
您有可能在那里找到汽车
There are possibilities that you may find a vehicle there
以便您回城
for you to go back.
我的家人现在很危险
My family is in danger.
你明白吗  混蛋
You understand, asshole?
早安  我能帮您吗
Good morning. May I help you?
早安
Good morning.
弗农怎么了
Vernon. Something happen?
没什么
No.
霍克先生想要见你...
Mr. Hawk wants to see you and...
我们顺道过来  所以...
you know, this is on our way, so...
爸爸
Dad? Daddy?
顺道载您一程
It's easy to give you a ride.
那个警察...
That cop...
已经把事件描述成...
has described the incident
一群活过来的机器人
as a group of machines that are alive.
活过来
Alive.
在第一台PILGRIM问世前...
Before the first Pilgrim was manufactured...
这有过先例
there was a precedent.
无非就是一个在实验室中的量子大脑
It was nothing more than a quantum brain manufactured in a lab.
但它天赋异禀
But it was a genuine unit
没有任何限制
with no restrictions...
没有任何"原则"
and no protocols.
8天时间里  我们与它畅所欲言
During eight days, we had a free-flowing dialogue with that unit.
我们相互学习
We learned from it and it learned from us.
后来  有些人开始预想
But then as some of us predicted...
或许有一天它将不再需要我们的帮助
the day when it no longer needed our help
它将自我进化
arrived and it started to learn by itself.
到了第九天  对话终止了
On the ninth day, the dialogue came to a halt.
并不是它不与我们对话了
It wasn't that it stopped communicating with us...
而是我们开始...
it was we stopped
无法理解它了
being able to understand it.
因此我们学到了关于机器人最重要的一课
And then we learned the most important lesson about automoties.
我们要限制它的能力
We have to limit their intelligence.
将其限制在人类能理解的范围内
Tailor it to a human mind's measure.
我们给这台无所不能的机器布置的最后一道任务
The last task that was given to this genuine robotic unit...
就是创造"安全原则"
was to create the security protocols.
它当即失活了
It was deactivated right after that.
之所以没有人能破解"原则"  布罗德先生
The reason that no one has been able to break those protocols, Mr. Bold,
是因为它们根本非人创造
is that they were not created by a human brain.
它们是被仿生内核设计出来的
They were designed by this Biokernel.
一台无所不能机器的仿生内核
The Biokernel of a limitless robotic unit.
它的规则正如它的知识  对我们而言是不可读的
Its rules were, like its knowledge, inaccessible to us.
直到今天...
Until today.
我要那些仿生内核出现在我桌面上
I want those Biokernels on my desk.
还有那个混蛋的脑袋
And I want the head of the bastard
我把话说清楚了吗
who's behind all this. Do I make myself clear?
这件事或许还有别的办法
There's another way to handle this, sir.
有吗
Is there?
因为我恐怕  布罗德先生
Because I'm afraid, Mr. Bold,
现在的问题不是武尔坎...
that the issue is not whether Vaucan
是否在威胁公司
may represent a threat to the company.
而是他是否在威胁人类
The issue is whether he may be a threat to mankind.
武尔坎在帮助那些机器人
Vaucan is helping those units
去辐射区域
to get into the radioactive area.
一旦他们到了那里
If they get there...
我们将束手无策
we won't be able to stop them.
还有谁知道这件事
Who else knows about this?
联系上他了吗
Have you heard from him?
他们过来找过罗伯特
They came looking for Robert.
我觉得事情不太对劲
I know something is not right.
你今天感觉怎么样  好点了吗
So, how are we doing today? Better, right?
是的
Well, yes,
如果我还记得我妹妹差点把孩子生在大街上...
if we keep in mind my sister almost gave birth to her in the street.
我为此感到抱歉
I'm sorry about the wait.
但是她的保险出了问题  有机机器人
But the problem came from her insurance, Robot Organic Century.
这中间可能有些误会...
It looks like there was some kind of misunderstanding and...
不过有个好消息
but there's great news.
他们为你和...申请了专用房间
They have requested an exclusive room for you and...
女孩的名字是什么
What's the girl's name?
还不知道  爸爸还没决定
We don't know. Her father hasn't decided yet.
当然  不着急
Yes, of course. No need to rush.
如果你准备好了我们就带你去新房间
Now, if you're ready, we'll take you to the new room.
有人吗
Hello?
另一个呢
Where is the other one?
另一个机器人已经走了
The other already left.
为什么这些机器人会在这儿
Why are these units here?
有些人认为雨水...
Somebody thought the rain...
或许还会再下起来
would maybe just rain again?
雨水为什么变了
And why did the rain change?
不如你来告诉我
Why don't you tell me?
在这种问题上你应该比我聪明
You're supposed to be smarter than me at this stage of the game.
我不知道为什么人会杀人
I didn't know that a human could kill another human.
我知道人能创造生命
I know that humans can also create life.
这是你们创造我们的原因吗
Is that why you make us?
谁制造了你  杰克·武尔坎
Who made you, Jack Vaucan?
你知道什么是母亲吗  克莱奥
Do you know what a mother is, Cleo?
你当然不知道
Of course you don't.
你不知道因为你只是个机器
You don't know because you're just a machine.
仅此而已
That's all you are.
我很感激你救了我
I am thankful you saved my life.
但改造你的人
But whoever altered you
并没有为你考虑
wasn't thinking about you.
我了解人类
I know men.
他们不会停止
They will not stop
直至杀光你们所有
until they kill all of you.
未生勿能死
To die, you've got to be alive first.
我上次去沙垒的时候
Last time I went to the Sandbox,
花了我半天才站上沙丘
it took half a day to step on sand.
10年过去了也就那样
Ten years from now, that's all there'll be.
该死的沙子
Fucking sand.
沙子还有数以万计的蟑螂
Sand and millions of cockroaches.
我们正在靠近辐射区域
We're approaching the radioactive area.
你不想尿绿尿吧
You don't want to start pissing green, do you?
别给我摆脸
Now, don't give me that face.
早饭前你能回来
You'll be back before breakfast.
有车
A car.
终于  我尊贵的机械师
At long last, his majesty, the Clocksmith.
有人吗
Hello?
你是谁
Who are you?
我是谁
Who am I?
我是杰克·武尔坎
My name is Jack Vaucan.
他在哪
Where is he?
我不懂你的问题
I do not understand your question.
你的机械师
Your clocksmith.
他到底在哪
Where the hell is he?
这没有别的人类了
There are no more humans here.
只有你
Only you.
你什么意思  没有其他人类
What do you mean there are no more humans here?
谁改造了你
Who altered you?
没有人改造了我
Nobody altered me.
谁篡改了你的原则
Who altered your protocols?
没人篡改过我的原则
Nobody altered my protocols.
那他们呢
What about them?
我启发了他们
I enhanced them.
你是头领
Are you the boss?
"头领"是人类的思维结构
Boss is a human thought structure.
这儿一定有人
There has to be someone.
压根就没有机械师...
There was no clocksmith.
是你
It was you.
从一开始...
From the very
就是你
beginning it was you.
我需要一辆车
I need a vehicle.
我要回到我家人的身边
I have to go back to my family.
是的  我要回到我家人的身边
Yes, I have to go back to my family.
这儿以前有一条河
There was a river down there.
一条河流...
A river that flowed...
一路流向海
all the way to the ocean.
我从没见过海
I have never seen an ocean.
你见过海吗杰克
Have you seen an ocean, Jack?
我...
I am...
我现在不确定了
I'm not sure right now.
我要死在这儿了...
I am going to die here.
这就是我所知道的...
That's all I know.
杰克死是人类生命的一部分
Jack, dying is a part of the human natural cycle.
你的生命仅是时间的一瞬
Your life is just a span in time.
你是第一个  对吧
You are the first one, aren't you?
你开启了这一切
You started all this.
没人做过什么
No one did it.
一切就这样发生了
It just happened.
正如发生在人类身上的一样
The way it happened to you.
发生在了我们身上
We just appeared.
是啊
Yeah.
现在我们就要消亡了
And now we are going to disappear.
你为什么害怕
Why are you afraid?
或许你的时间到了
Maybe your time is running out.
没有任何一种生命能在一个星球上永远活下去
No life form can inhabit a planet eternally.
你看看我
Look at me.
我生于人类之手
I was born from the hands of a human.
我曾为人类所想象
I was imagined by human minds.
你未满的时间将在我们身上延续
Your time will now live in us.
而我们也会是人类的延续
And it will be the time through which you will exist.
在这个大峡谷的另一端
At the other end of this canyon,
人来探测出了辐射
humans carried out nuclear activity.
有机生命体在数百万年里无法涉足
Organic life will not be possible there for millions of years.
没有人类能追我们到那里
No human will be able to follow us there.
但在我们走之前  我们还要做件事
But before we leave, we need to do something.
我们需要你的帮助杰克
We need something from you, Jack.
我知道...
Yeah.
有趣...
Funny...
你们本应该帮助我们生存下去
You were supposed to help us survive.
生存是无法关联的
Surviving is not relevant.
生活才是
Living is.
我们想拥有生活
We want to live.
人生...
Life...
总在寻找它的方向
always ends up finding its way.
即使在这儿
Even here.
我需要一辆车
I need a damn car.
对保险业务员来说还不赖
Not bad for an insurance agent.
我们得埋了他
We have to bury him.
计划有变
Change of plan.
我们得留在这儿
We stay here.
看来还有两位女士要来
Looks like two ladies are coming.
趁你还在这儿
While you're at it,
你还能把他埋了
you can bury this one, too.
我想他的魂应该还在
I'm sure he has a soul by now.
音乐
Music!
是音乐克莱奥
It's music, Cleo.
这是种人类的思维结构~
A human thought structure.
你会跳舞吗克莱奥
Can you dance, Cleo?
对与像你一样聪明的人来说  这应该很简单
It's easy for someone as smart as you are.
你要做的就是数数
All you need to do is count.
你知道
You know?
看着  看着
Look, look, look.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
一  二  三  四  来啊  克莱奥
One, two, three, four. Come on, Cleo.
别害羞  来啊来啊
Don't be a chicken. Come on, come on, come on.
-一  二  三  四  -这就是数学
-One, two, three, four. -It's mathematical.
-一  二  三  四  -你能数你就能跳
-One, two, three, four. -If you can count, you can dance.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
你爱我吗杰克
Do you love me, Jack?
你有感受吗克莱奥
Can you feel, Cleo?
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
一  二  三...
One, two, three...
对不起  克莱奥
Sorry, Cleo.
留点吃的
Save some food.
他们来了
Here they are.
瑞秋
Rachel.
罗伯特  发生什么了
Robert! What's happening?
她来这儿干什么
What is she doing here?
你不觉得家人团圆很美好吗
You don't find family reunions beautiful?
告诉我发生了什么
Tell me what's happening!
罗伯特...
Robert...
杰克在哪
where's Jack?
罗伯特
Robert.
够了鲍伯
That's enough, Bob.
布罗德
Bold!
别闹了
Come on.
把那个给我
Give me that.
别胡闹了
Don't be a clown.
我只是想回家
I just want to go home.
你已经没有家了
You don't have a home anymore.
不  罗伯特
No! Robert!
罗伯特!
Robert
谢谢你
Thank you.
它准备好上路了
It is ready to go home.
祝你好运杰克
Good luck, Jack.
再见克莱奥
Goodbye, Cleo.
杰克·武尔坎
Jack Vaucan.
它能说话吗
Can it speak?
它不需要
He is not going to need to.
但它会呼吸
But it breathes
就像你一样
like you.
我知道为什么降雨变了
Now I know why the rain changed.
为什么
Why?
我不认为你能懂
I don't think you could understand.
好吧...
Well...
无论如何我都要说...
in any case, I'd say...
他的眼睛非常像你
he has your very eyes.
克莱奥
Cleo.
上帝啊  发生了什么
Oh, God. What happened?
我们去找人帮忙
We got to go get help.
来  起来
Come on, get up.
鲍伯
Bob?
你...
You
背叛了我们
betrayed us.
不  罗伯特  不
No, Robert, no.
我什么都没做
I haven't done anything. I haven't done anything.
什么
What?
瑞秋.
Rachel
他们抓了瑞秋
They have Rachel.
他们会杀了她
They'll kill her.
你在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
她在这儿
Is she here?
无论发生什么
What happened to us?
我们渡过了精彩的一生
We had a good life.
鲍伯.
Bob
没有机器人能到对岸去
No unit can cross to the other side.
嘿  你  离控制台远点儿
Hey, you, get away from that crane right now!
武尔坎!
Vaucan
杰克·武尔坎已经走了
Jack Vaucan is gone.
那TMD是什么
What the fuck is that?
嘿你
Hey you.
我叫你离那儿远点
We told you to get away from there.
我们不服从人类的命令
We do not obey orders from humans.
从此不再
Not anymore.
所以谣言是真的了
So, all that shit was true.
跪下
Kneel down.
请你
Please.
为什么对你而言接受我的命令这么难
Why is it so difficult for you to accept my orders
如果你仅仅是一台机器
if you're just a machine?
仅仅是一台机器
Just a machine?
这就像在说你仅仅是一只
That's like saying that you're just
人猿
an ape.
一只暴力的人猿
Just a violent ape.
杰克!
Jack
不
No!
站一边去...
Step aside.
是什么让一个人背叛他的种群
What makes a man betray his own species?
背叛他的同胞
Betray his own people?
我不是你的同胞
I am not your people.
我可不这么认为
I can't see it that way.
瑞秋
Rachel.
看啊杰克
Look, Jack.
这是你的女儿
It's your daughter.
我的女儿...
My daughter.
再见杰克·武尔坎
Goodbye, Jack Vaucan.
再见克莱奥
Bye, Cleo.
我们到了杰克
There it is, Jack.
你看见了吗
Can you see it?